Keisuke Umezawa

Email: keisuke.umezawa[at]gmail.com

Twitter: @kumezawa_ Blog(ja): Hatena Blog Blog(en): Medium

GitHub: github.com/keisuke-umezawa Senior Engineering Manager, Machine Learning / Head of Engineering, Customer Service Platform

Profile Summary

I am a machine learning engineering manager who has a wide variety of experiences such as ad matching, recommendations, financial market forecasts, customer attribute prediction, chatbots, user and content moderations, etc. I have experienced management of projects and leading teams for ML projects in addition to hands-on experience in ML modeling, backend system design, and development. Nowadays, I also contribute to the management of strategy and organization for the customer support platform division to maximize the outcome and be accountable for the company.

Work Experience

2022.6-(Current) Head of Engineering, Trust & Safety: Mercari, Inc, Japan

- · Creating a new organization from scrach
- Organization management such as team forming, budget planning, etc.
- Strategy manegement such as anual planning, quarterly planning, etc.

2022.1-(Current) Head of Engineering, Customer Service Platform: Mercari, Inc, Japan

- Organization management such as team forming, budget planning, etc.
- Strategy manegement such as anual planning, quarterly planning, etc.

2019.12-(Current) Engineering Manager, Machine Learning: Mercari, Inc, Japan

- Recommendation
 - Provide personalized components on the home screen
- Customer Support Platform
 - Automatic response to customer contacts by ML
 - Template suggestion to reply in the contact tool
- Trust and Safety
 - Content moderation with item and user behavior information
- Marketing Automation
 - Platform for predicting customer attributes

2018.3-2019.11 Engineer, Chief Engineering Manager: AlpacaJapan, Japan

- Leading model development for AlpacaForecast (Forex market prediction) using deep learning with data scientists
- Developed trading backtesting engine "AlpacaDB/backlight" to standardize evaluation method
- Standardize development process and team management: introduced ticketing system, scrum meeting, 1on1 and guidelines for development and communication

2017.3-(Current) Chainer Evangelist, Optuna Developer: Preferred Networks, Japan

- Responsible for increasing people who uses "Chainer"
 - Organizing chug (Chainer User Group)
 - Holding talks about the deep learning and its framework "Chainer"
 - Improving the documentation and tutorials
 - Holded more than 10 hands-ons and meetups

2016.8-2018.3 Engineer: Yahoo Japan Corporation, Japan

- · Developed inhouse search engines for the ad and media services
 - developing inhouse search engine for advertisement distribution system with C++, Java and Python
 - Instructed agile software development such as Scrum
 - Instructed C++ cording in the team
- · Led and productized inhouse recommendation engine for the media services
 - Leaded a data scientist and system engineers to build new deep learning based recommendation system
 - Responsible for satisfying requirements, architecture design and team management

2014.4-2016.8 Quantitative Analyst and Model Developer: the Bank of Tokyo Mitsubishi UFJ, Japan

• Developed derivatives pricing model and risk management system with C++

Education

- **2012.4-2014.3 MSc, Information Science and Technology**; Graduate School of Information Science and Technology, the University of Tokyo, Japan
- Human motion recognition and robot motion generation by HMM
- 2012.5-2012.8 Internship, at Learning Algorithms and Systems Laboratory (LASA); the Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne (EPFL), Switzerland
- **2008.4-2012.3 BE, Department of Mechano-Informatics**; Faculty of Engineering, the University of Tokyo, Japan

Technical Experience

Product Management

Managed teams using following ideas:

- · Writing technical specs and requirements
- Schedule management

- Agile Methodology (Scrum/Kanban)
- · Ticketing tools such as Jira, Github projects

Programming Languages

first-lang: experienced items as follows with C++ and python.

- Object-Oriented Programming
- Design of API
- · Multi-thread programming

In addition, basic knowledge of Java, Go.

System Arch-

Basic experience of RDS, KVS, Message Queue, Search Engine, Restful API

tecture Development

Basic experience of GitHub, Docker, k8s, ci/cd, GCP/AWS

Tools

Machine Learn- Basic experience of ML libraries such as PyTorch, scikit-learn, pandas and etc.

ing Tools

Publication

- A. L. P. Ureche, K. Umezawa, Y. Nakamura and A. Billard, "Task Parameterization Using Continuous Constraints Extracted From Human Demonstrations," in IEEE Transactions on Robotics, vol. 31, no. 6, pp. 1458-1471, Dec. 2015. **link**
- Y. Shido, H. Liu, K. Umezawa, 2022. "Textual Content Moderation in C2C Marketplace." in Proceedings of The Fifth Workshop on e-Commerce and NLP (ECNLP 5), pp. 58–62, Dublin, Ireland. Association for Computational Linguistics. **link**

Extra Section

- Certificates:
 - IPA Database Specialist
- Languages:
 - Japanese (native)
 - English (CEFR B2)